# Luis Herrera

#### Colombia



linkedin.com/in/lh1008



https://github.com/lh1008



1209@holbertonschool.com



3057128788

## Summary

I am a cryptocurrency--particularly privacy-focused Monero--enthusiast. As a prominent Monero Community member since 2018, I translate Monero documents and organize communities. My primary focus is open-source software, and I have been studying and working with Linux operating systems since 2016.

Having studied and finished my Software Engineering foundations at Holberton School Colombia, I am working to integrate cryptocurrencies like Monero (XMR) with the world. Because cryptocurrency is new, this is both a technical and creative endeavor. I see and love technology as a bridge for human integration.

I know the C, Python, and JavaScript programming languages. I have done web development with HTML and CSS, and have experience in database management using MySQL.

## **Experience**



### Communication Group Coordinator (Volunteer)

Jul 2018 - Present (2 years 1 month +)

Workgroup production coordinator. Organize translators, transcriptionist's workload and publish final content throughout the community.

# Web Developer

Sabor Skateboards

Jun 2020 - Jul 2020 (2 months)

A HTML, CSS, and JavaScript project. My task included server deployment and site management.

# Software Engineer

**Holberton School** 

Sep 2019 - Jun 2020 (10 months)

Full-time programmer. Experience with C, Python, and Javascript programming languages, and database management with MySQL (SQLalchemy).

# Database Analyst

**EMCALI - Telecomunicaciones** 

Sep 2016 - Feb 2018 (1 year 6 months)

Database analyst. I also did the Geographic Information System software (GEOVISOR/MapInfo) colleagues training. My main task was to maintain the database information updated using the integrated OPEN-SmartFlex software. Databases were handled using Microsoft Excel crossed-based between different government official databases (FOSYGA, RUAF, DIAN, and PROCURADURIA).

# Business Development Administrator

**Productos Vrinda** 

Feb 2013 - May 2016 (3 years 4 months)

Production and service manager. My responsibilities were to cover the customer service area, staff planning, purchase, storage, and sales. I had to contact suppliers, make the financial accounting control, have resource optimization, and comply with quality standards and regulations of the food and beverage sector.

#### Georeferencer

Servinformación

Feb 2010 - Feb 2013 (3 years 1 month)

My task was to homologate the national property number in the company's databases to the EMCALI subscriber. I also made routing fieldwork through Geographic Information Systems (GIS). Geographic software layer control, collector supervisor, and location coordinates updates. Software: MapInfo, Excel, Access.

### **R** Commercial Director

Chef en tu Casa

2012 - 2012 (1 year)

Logistics, purchases, accounting, and cash management.

## **CSR**

Kimeline

Dec 2010 - Mar 2011 (4 months)

**Customer Service Representative** 

#### Education

# **Holberton School**

Software Engineer, Programming

2019 - 2021

# Udemy Academy

Web Designer, Web Development

2017 - 2018

Design, update, and web structure development using HTML and CSS. SEO positioning, CSS and 3D animations. Domain hosting and account management.



### Economics, Economy

2006 - 2017

The economics career analyzes the individual and his social-economic behavior. The implementation of econometric analysis is essential for understanding social organization.

### **Licenses & Certifications**

### Berlitz Proficiency Test - BERLITZ

Issued Dec 2012 - Expires Dec 2014

#### **Skills**

English • Customer Service • Team Leadership • MapInfo Professional • C (Programming Language) • Python (Programming Language) • JavaScript • MySQL • Programming • Open Source Software